Jimin George

Chief Accountant-Finance Incharge (Pre-Opening Expert)

Millennium Resort, Salalah - Oman | +968 9495 4561 | jimingeorge@ymail.com in www.linkedin.com/in/jimingeorge1605

Summary

Experienced Chief Accountant and acting finance manager reporting to General Manager with more than 11 years of demonstrated history of working in the hospitality industry. Skilled in Financial Reporting, Budgeting, F&B Cost, Payable, Income, Credit and Payroll Management as well as a pre-opening expert. Strong finance professional with a Bachelor of Commerce (B.Com) focused in Accounting and Finance from Mahatma Gandhi University Kerala, India

Work experience

Chief Accountant / Finance Incharge Sept. 2018 - Present Millennium Resort (5*) Salalah - Oman (Pre-Opening)

Ensures accurate and timely submission of information to the management, controls banks and all hotel money, ensures proper controls for cash handling, and brings any discrepancies to the attention of the concerned as well as the general ledger reconciliation. Assist forecasting and budgeting and make sure all work is carried out in accordance with hotel accounting and financial controls under the supervision and functional guidance, within the policies and procedures as outlined and the hotel's business plan and coordinating with external/internal auditors in timely manner.

Chief Accountant (Pre-Opening) Bayat by Cristal (5*) Abha - KSA

Work with the financial controller to provide full and accurate forecasting and budgeting proposals within the hotel. Ensures accurate and timely submission of information to the management, as well as the general ledger reconciliation. Make sure all work is carried out in accordance with hotel accounting and financial controls under the supervision and functional guidance, within the policies and procedures as outlined and the hotel's business plan and coordinating with external/internal auditors in timely manner.

Cost Controller (Pre-Opening)

Jan. 2014 - May 2017

June 2017 - Sept. 2018

Salalah Rotana Resort (5*) Salalah - Oman

Provide oversight of all financial aspects of Food and Beverage operations as well as the operational expenditures and to work with F&B operating

Core Competencies

- More than eight years of professional experience in financial and cost management
- Three years of comprehensive practical knowledge in expense treatment and income auditing
- Excellent interpersonal with effective oral and written communication skills.
- Ability to establish and sustain effective and positive working relationships.
- Strong management skills, work ethic, consensus gathering skills, and organisational skills.
- Successful team leader and motivator.

Skills

Computer Skills

• Sun System Ver. 6.0: Expert • Opera: Expert • Micros: Expert • Simphony: Expert Oasys H2A: Expert **Expert** • Bayan: • FMC: Expert • FBM: Expert • MS Office: Expert

On Job Competitive Skills

- Budget & Forecasting
- Expenditure Treatment
- Cash Flow Management
- Credit Management

departments on a daily basis to provide analysis of financial performance, implement and monitor controls, verify purchases/expenses and review reported revenues. Ensure all the practices are to be performed in accordance with departmental and policies, practices, and procedures.

- Income/Revenue
 Management
- F&B Cost Control
- Payroll

Cost Control Clerk

Dec. 2011 - Jan. 2014

Park Rotana & Park Arjaan (5*) Abu Dhabi – U.A.E

Support the cost controller in the managing the hotel's daily financial and cost control activities, manages the day to day activities, co-ordinates functions and activates with personnel in accounting and in operational departments by assisting receiving & inventory. Under the general guidance of the cost controller and within the limits of hotel Policy and Procedure, being responsible for overall cost control operation and administration including the preparation or reporting and relevant record keeping.

Receiving Clerk

Nov. 2010 - Dec. 2011

Millennium Hotel (5*) Doha - Qatar

Responsible for receiving all goods such as food and beverage and General according to the standards established by the hotel, based on purchase order and/or market list, check all deliveries for quality, quantity, price, box weight and expiry for food and beverage items and strictly adherence to the Hotel's policy on Hygiene, Health & Safety .To prepare daily receiving reports for all goods received in the system as well as liaison with accounts payable as required

Education

Bachelor of Commerce, Financial Accounting 2007 - 2010 Mahatma Gandhi University

Kerala - India

Career Developments

- Financial Accountant, Trained for 3 months and relieved. (Salalah Rotana)
- Income Auditor, Trained and relieved for 2 months. (Salalah Rotana)
- Accounts Receivable, Trained and relived for 2 months (Salalah Rotana)
- Cost Controller, Two months Reliever (Amwaj Rotana Hotel Dubai)- Task Force.
- Cost Controller, Six months Training & Reliever (Park Rotana Hotel Abu Dhabi)
- Store Keeper, Three months Reliever (Millennium Hotel Doha)
- Receiving Clerk, One Month Reliever (Park Rotana Hotel Abu Dhabi)
- Others Routine Training in Hospitality, Leadership & Management skills etc.

Career Achievements

• Team leader in setting up all the areas of finance dept. as a Pre- opening team member with the capacity of chief accountant at Salalah Oman in

Languages

English: FluentHindi: ModerateMalayalam: FluentTamil: Moderate

Key Strengths

- Strongly believe in honesty and loyalty towards the organization
- Highly motivated and willing to learn more to achieve organizational goal
- Can be an effective team member
- Believe in "Quality of work as well in Quantity"

Personnel Details

• Nationality: Indian

• Date of Birth: 16th May

1988

• Age: 32

Marital Status: Married

Passport Details

Number: U 0772434
 Date of Issue: 03.2020
 Date of Expiry: 03.2030

Place of Issue : Muscat(Oman) 2018

- Team leader in setting up all the areas of finance dept. as a Pre- opening team member with the capacity of chief accountant at Abha KSA in 2017.
- Lead in a pre-opening emplacement of cost control and store departments in a flagship property of Rotana at Salalah Oman in 2014.
- Suggested, coordinated and accomplished a consolidated food, beverage, general, supplies quote comparison for three sister hotels which are under Taqah hotel management company and implemented which made a good impact on the hotel cost management plan for the period of 2015-16.

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above information is correct as per my knowledge.

Jimin George

Salalah, Oman

